roaring.earth 2019-05-13

# Privacy Policy

Protecting your personal information is our priority. This Privacy Policy applies to the Roaring Earth LLC (“Roaring Earth”, “us” or “we”) website currently located at www.roaring.earth (the “Site”) and governs data collection and usage through the Site. By using the Site, you consent to the data practices described in this Privacy Policy.

**Collection and Use of Personally Identifiable Information:**

Roaring Earth does not currently ask Site users to provide personally identifiable information directly to Roaring Earth, except in the following instances: 

  1. If you reside outside of the European Economic Area you may submit content to Roaring Earth or to the Site and you must provide an email address as part of the submission process. Roaring Earth may use this personally identifiable information to contact you regarding the uploaded materials, other matters relating to this Site or Roaring Earth’s business, or matters which Roaring Earth believes will be of interest to you.
  2. We use MailChimp to manage our newsletter and other email lists. MailChimp is an active participant of the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework that regulates the correct and protected data transfer of personal data.  MailChimp’s privacy policy is available at <http://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy>.

**Collection and Use of Non-Personally Identifiable Information:**

Roaring Earth collects and uses information about your interactions with the Site in way that does not identify you as an individual (“non-personally identifiable information”). Roaring Earth may collect, use, and disclose non-personally identifiable information in a variety of ways such as the following:

“Cookies” etc. – Technologies such as cookies, log files, web beacons/clear gifs, device identifiers, tags, and scripts are used by Roaring Earth and our partners such as marketing partners, advertisers, affiliates, or analytics or service providers. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the Site, tracking users’ movements around the Site, to serve ads based on a user’s prior visits to the Site and other sites on the Internet, and to gather aggregate metrics such as total number of visitors, traffic, and demographic patterns across the Site or portions of the Site. Roaring Earth may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis. The information collected is non-personally identifiable information. 

Roaring Earth may use “automatically collected” information and “cookies” information, alone or in combination with other information we have collected from you. This non-personally identifiable information includes information about your computer hardware and software, such as your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times and referring website addresses. This information is used to help us in providing the Site and to operate the Roaring Earth business, including to: (a) personalize your experience on the Site, such as to provide content we think you may be interested in based on your prior Site usage; (b) provide customized third party advertisements, content, and information; (c) monitor and analyze the effectiveness of the Site and third party marketing activities; (d) monitor aggregate site usage metrics, track movements around the Site and analyze trends and demographic information; and (e) for other Site related purposes.

**Disclosure**

Roaring Earth may disclose your information to third-party service providers for the purpose of providing the Site, if required to do so by law, subpoena or if we believe that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the law or comply with legal process served on Roaring Earth or the Site; (b) investigate, prevent, or take action regarding suspected or actual illegal activities; (c) protect and defend the rights, property or security of Roaring Earth and/or the Site;  (d) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of Roaring Earth, or the public, or (e) to enforce the [Terms of Use](https://www.goodreads.com/about/terms) for the Site.

**Advertising**

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit the Site and on our behalf across the Internet. These companies may use non-personally identifiable information (not including your name, address email address or telephone number) about your visits to the Site and other web sites and mobile applications to provide ads about goods and services of interest to you (“Tracking Technologies”). Tracking Technologies may include web log data (such as IP address and information about your browser or operating system) or place or recognition of a unique cookie on your browser to enable you to receive customized ads. Through this process, demographic or other interest data may be associated with your browser or device in a non-personally identifiable manner. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/) [www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/).

Roaring Earth also works with third party service providers to monitor certain pages of the Site for purposes such as reporting traffic and other advertising statistics. These third party providers may use cookies and/or other monitoring technologies to compile anonymous statistics about our visitors. No personally identifiable information is transferred to these third party service providers.

**Social Media Widgets**  
The Site includes the ability to use functions provided by third party social media networks (such as Likes, Shares or commenting). As further described below in Links to Other Websites, the operation and data collected through use of these features are governed by the privacy policy of the third party providing it, and not by this Privacy Policy.

**Links to Other Websites**

The Site contains links to websites and services provided by third parties. Any information that you provide or that is collected on third party sites or services is provided directly to that third party and is subject to that third party’s privacy policies. Roaring Earth is not responsible for any aspect of the third party sites or services linked to from the Site, including their content, privacy or security practices. We encourage you to learn about third parties’ privacy and security policies before providing them with personally identifiable information. You should read the third party website’s policies before using their service or providing them with information.

**Security of the Website**

Roaring Earth uses commercially reasonable physical, managerial, and technical safeguards designed to protect the Website and the information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. While Roaring Earth strives to protect your information, we cannot guarantee the security of such information.

**Children under Thirteen**

Roaring Earth does not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of thirteen. No one under age 13 is allowed to provide any personal information to the Site. 

**Merger or Sale**

If Roaring Earth or Site-related assets are sold to or acquired by or merged with a third-party entity, we reserve the right to transfer or assign the information that we have collected from users as part of that merger, acquisition, sale, or other change of control event.

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**

If Roaring Earth updates this Privacy Policy, the changes will be posted on the Site with an updated “Last Modified” date. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective on the date posted on the Site as shown in the “Last Modified” date at the bottom of this Privacy Policy, and your use of the Site after that date signifies your agreement to be bound by the changes. You should check the Site regularly to stay up to date on any changes. 

**Contact Roaring Earth**

Roaring Earth welcomes your questions or comments regarding this Privacy Policy and the Site. You can reach Roaring Earth by email at  [Info@roaring.earth](mailto:info@roaring.earth).

Last modified September 20, 2018
